Guide to the Rice University Early Land Deeds, Contracts and Related Records, 1830-1969 UA 222
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series I: Rice Land Deeds, 1830-1966; 144825; 39 Linear Feet
  - Texas Counties, 144826
    - Robertson County, 144898
      - Lease, 16 acres in Calvert to W.W. Purdom, Robertson Co., 1940, 1945, 144918 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Lease, 7 acres in Calvert to P.A. Knapp, Robertson Co., 1940-1950, 144917 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Lease, 7 acres in Calvert to Mrs. Julia Moore, Robertson Co., 1944-1950, 144916 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - Notes of Old Town Property, Robertson Co., 1908-1917, 144915 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Deeds, titles, papers, town lots in Bremond, Robertson Co., 1922, 144914 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Litigation for recovery of Bremond lots, Robertson Co., 1922-1923, 144913 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Acknowledgements of tenancy, Calvert, Robertson Co., 1925, 144912 (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Reconveyance, R.E. Chance, Calvert, Robertson Co., 1929-1932, 144911 (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Cancelled deeds, Robertson Co., 1921-1923, 144910 (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Reconveyances, deeds, title papers, Robertson Co., 1929-1956, 144902
        - Correspondence concerning title to lot 4, block 22, Calvert, Robertson Co., 1929, 144909 (Box 33, Folder 16, Subfolder 1)
        - Reconveyance of lot 10, block 92 by Pete Scoba, Bremond, Robertson Co., 1935, 144908 (Box 33, Folder 16, Subfolder 2)
        - Reconveyance of lot 5, block 75, Bremond, Robertson Co., 1939, 144907 (Box 33, Folder 16, Subfolder 3)
        - Deed and reconveyance, lots 3-5, block 94, Bremond, Robertson Co., 1956, 144906 (Box 33, Folder 16, Subfolder 4)
        - Easement to Gulf States Utilities Company, concerning line of poles in Calvert, Robertson Co., 1931, 144905 (Box 33, Folder 16, Subfolder 5)
        - Lots 8-9, block 157, Calvert, Robertson Co., 1935, 144904 (Box 33, Folder 16, Subfolder 6)
        - Reconveyance, lot 10, block 92, Bremond, Robertson Co., 1935, 144903 (Box 33, Folder 16, Subfolder 7)
      - Reconveyance, lots 1-3, block 120, Bremond, Robertson Co., 1929-1933, 144900 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - Reconveyance, lot 3, block 75, Bremond, Robertson Co., 1957, 144901 (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Various deeds and title papers, Robertson Co., 1906-1923, 144899 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Sabine County, 144892
      - T.L.L. Temple claim vs. Rice Institute, James A. Curry League, Sabine Co., 1908-1910, 144897 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Estates of Gilbert Mackechney & W.W. McElroy, lands sold to T.L.L. Temple, Sabine Co., 1899-1900, 144896 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - James A. Curry League, Sabine Co., 1880-1907, 144895 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Larkin Groce/James A. Curry League, Sabine Co., 1899-1907, 144894 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Sale, 13,096.5 acres to T.L.L. Temple, Sabine Co., 1899-1910, 144893 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - San Patricio County, 144889
      - M.J.P. & Delgado Survey, San Patricio Co., 1902, 1907, 144891 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Sale, 1170 acres of Delgado Survey to M.K. Wright, San Patricio Co., 1908-1910, 144890 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Tyler County, 144850
      - Abstract, Survey No. 1, Blk. 6, Tyler Co., 1909, 144888 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Abstract, Survey No. 9, Tyler Co., 1909, 144887 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Sale, 20 acres in Texas Central Railway Survey to D.J. Gray, Tyler Co., 1920, 144886 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Sale, timber on 6,750 acres in various surveys to Nona Fletcher & Kirby Lumber Company, Tyler Co., 1922-1937, 144885 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Sale, timber on 1,280 acres in Charles Stewart Survey to P.H. Nolen, Tyler and Hardin Counties, 1913, 144884 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Sale, timber on 599 acres of Texas Central Railway Survey to Southern Lumber Company, 1937, 144883 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Sale, timber on 100 acres in I & GN Railroad Survey to Southern Lumber Company, Tyler Co., 1937, 144882 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Sale, timber on 1280 acres in Charles Stewart Survey to Oscar Baker, Tyler and Hardin Counties, 1922-1939, 144881 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Sale, timber on 640 acres in Texas Central Railway Survey to G.B. Risinger, Tyler Co., 1916, 1919, 144880 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Sale, 65 acres in Nancy Skillern Survey to Kirby Lumber Co., Tyler Co., 1958, 144879 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Lease, pasture, 640 acres in J. Sims Survey to A.V. Bell, Tyler Co., 1961-1962, 144878 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Lease, 40 acres in Tabitha Sumrall Survey to Gus Kirkwood, Tyler Co, 1960-1963, 144877 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Lease, 598 acres in Texas Central Railway Survey to R.I. Reid, Tyler Co., 1941, 144876 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Sale, timber on 7190 acres of various surveys to Texas Creosoting Company, Tyler Co., 1947-1950, 144875 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Sale, 12 acres in Texas Central Railway Survey to East Texas and Gulf Railway, Tyler Co., 1917, 144874 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - Tyler County lands, 1899-1925, 144872
        - Johnathan Judson Survey conflict, 1922, 144873 (Box 36, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Tyler County lands, 1899-1942, 144869
        - Report of J.R. Risinger on Tyler County lands, 1931, 144871 (Box 36, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
        - Lawsuit, Rice Institute vs. Morgan Smith, 1941-1942, 144870 (Box 36, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - Tyler County lands, various field notes, 1882-1934, 144868 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Tyler County lands, 1917-1954, 144858
        - Old and new memoranda and correspondence concerning correct acreage owned by Rice Institute on the B.B.B. & C.R.R. Company by H.M. Smith & M Sharp Surveys, 1917-1944, 144867 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 1)
        - Easement to the State Highway Commission for right-of-way, 1931, 144866 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 2)
        - Easement to Gulf States Utilities for power line right-of-way, 1930, 144865 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 3)
        - Lawsuit, Addie Nolan, et al vs. Rice Institute involving tithe to Radford Odom Survey, 1937-1938, 144864 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 4)
        - Fire protection agreement, 6638 acres, 1935-1936, 144863 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 5)
        - Tennessee Gas Transmission Company, right-of-way agreement, 1949-1950, 144862 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 6)
        - Southwestern Bell telephone agreement for telephone line, 1953-1954, 144861 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 7)
        - Gulf States Utilities Company, copy of easement for electric line right-of-way, 1949, 144860 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 8)
        - State of Texas right-of-way for various roads, 1949, 144859 (Box 36, Folder 4, Subfolder 9)
      - Tyler County lands, 1908, 1925-1951, 144852
        - Humble Oil and Refining, right-of-way, 1951, 144857 (Box 36, Folder 5, Subfolder 1)
        - Released oil, gas and mineral leases, 1938-1948, 144856 (Box 36, Folder 5, Subfolder 2)
        - Gulf States Utilities Company, electric powerline easement, 1950, 144855 (Box 36, Folder 5, Subfolder 3)
        - Gulf States Utilities Company, right-of-way along Dollarsville road, 1951, 144854 (Box 36, Folder 5, Subfolder 4)
        - Easement contract with Atlantic Pipeline Company, 1931, 1944, 144853 (Box 36, Folder 5, Subfolder 5)
      - Leases or acknowledgements of tenancy, Tyler Co., 1908-1934, 144851 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Walker County, 144848
      - Quit Claim Deed, Rice Institute to W.L. Smither, R. Sparks Survey, Walker Co., 1930, 144849 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Waller County, 144831
      - Abstract, J.F. Martin Survey, Waller Co., 1911, 144847 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Sale, 213 acres in J.F. Martin Survey to James Miller, Waller Co., 1895-1915, 144846 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Sale, 216 acres in Thomas Stevens Survey to Alfred Yarbrough, Waller Co., 1912-1913, 144845 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Sale, timber on 4076 acres in John Stephens League to Grogan-Cochran Lumber Company, Waller Co., 1929, 144844 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Sale, 102 acres in J.F. Martin Survey to W.M. Bennatt, Waller Co., 1915, 1918, 144843 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Sale, timber on J.M. Stephens Survey to general Box Company, Waller Co., 1943, 144842 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Lease, oil and gas in J. Groce Survey to Fred K. Foster, Victor Prassel and Jeff Shelburne, Waller Co., 1943-1944, 144841 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Sale, 64 acres in John M. Stephens Survey to Houston Lighting and Power Company, Waller Co., 1962, 144840 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Sale, timber on 4070 acres in John M. Stephens Survey to Timber Lumber Company, Waller Co., 1948-1951, 144839 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Sale, 4070 acres in John M. Stephens Survey to M.E. Shifleit, Morgan L. Price, John Martin, Travis Marks, et al, Waller Co. 1957-1959, 144838 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Sale, timber on John M. Stephens Survey to O.P. Perkins and William Rodgerson, Waller Co., 1933 (no content), 144837 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Waller County lands, 1890-1907, 1933-1936, 144834
        - Oil and mineral lease with H.R. Cullen, 144836 (Box 37, Folder 13, Subfolder 1)
        - Town of Hempstead, list of lots, blocks and titles, 1890, 1907, 144835 (Box 37, Folder 13, Subfolder 2)
      - Johnathan M. Stephens Survey, lease field notes, correspondence, surveys, 1856-1934, 144833 (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - Johnathan M. Stephens Survey, correspondence, notes, agreements concerning oil and pasturage leases, 1933-1937, 144832 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Wharton County, 144827
      - Peter B. Norton Survey, Wharton Co., 1906-1908, 144830 (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - Sale, 284 acres in Norton Survey to Putnam Brothers, Wharton Co., 1908, 144829 (Box 37, Folder 17)
      - Sale, 382 acres in various surveys to J.F. Wilson, Wharton and Matagorda Counties, 1924-1929, 144828 (Box 37, Folder 18)
- Series II: Rice Institute Papers (Working Rice papers - including some deeds), 1891-1966; 144456; 29 Linear Feet
  - Campus Construction, 1910-1940; 144651; 5.3 Linear Feet
    - Receipts and correspondence, William Miller and Sons, for Admin building construction, 1910-1912, 144824 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Vouchers and drafts, William Miller and Sons, 1912, 144822
      - Fidelity and Deposit Company of Maryland, 1913, 144823 (Box 38, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
    - Cram, Goodhue and Ferguson. Architects of Rice Institute, 1909-1914, 144817
      - Concerning General Plans for Rice Institute, 1909-1910, 144821 (Box 38, Folder 3, Folder 1)
      - Vouchers and Correspondence, 1910-1914, 144820 (Box 38, Folder 3, Subfolder 2)
      - Vouchers and Correspondence, 1910-1914, 144819 (Box 38, Folder 3, Subfolder 3)
      - Vouchers and Correspondence, 1912, 144818 (Box 38, Folder 3, Subfolder 4)
    - Contracts, orders and estimates for Administration and Mechanical buildings, 1911-1914, 144803
      - Orders and estimates, 1913-1914, 144816 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 1)
      - William F. Ross, furniture for Administration building, 1912-1913, 144815 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 2)
      - Layne and Bower, Co., for drilling Artesian well, 1910, 144814 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 3)
      - Order with Oswald J. Lassing for carving tea vases, 1913, 144813 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 4)
      - Order with Oswald J. Lassing for carving of capitals and columns, 1913, 144812 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 5)
      - Moravian Potter and Tile Works, 1912, 144811 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 6)
      - W.G. Cornell, plumbing, 1911-1913, 144810 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 7)
      - F.E. Newberry Electric Company for electrical work, 1911-1913, 144809 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 8)
      - Collins Brothers Company for heating in Admin. building, 144808 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 9)
      - Bowker-Torrey Company to furnish marble, 1912, 144807 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 10)
      - Houston Structural Steel Company, 1911, 144806 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 11)
      - Hixon Electric Company, Mechanical Lab, 1914, 144805 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 12)
      - Detroit Heating and Lighting, for Mechanical Lab, 1912, 144804 (Box 38, Folder 4, Subfolder 13)
    - Contract #1 with William Minter and Sons for Administration building, 1910-1912, 144802 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Contract #2 with William Minter and Sons for Mechanical building, 1910-1912, 144801 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Receipts and payments to Wilmer Waldo on contract for drains and sewers, 1911, 144800 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Receipts, vouchers and estimates on construction of various institute buildings, 1911-1913:, 144789
      - Vouchers and paid estimates for Mechanical Lab and Power House, 1911-1912, 144799 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
      - Vouchers to Pittsburgh Testing Laboratory, 1911, 144798 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - Contract and vouchers to F.E. Newberry Electric Company for work on Mechanical Lab and Power House, 1911-1913, 144797 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 3)
      - Contract and vouchers to W.G. Cornell Company for plumbing in Mechanical Lab and Power House, 1911-1913, 144796 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 4)
      - Bonds, vouchers and contracts to Collins Brothers Company for heating in Mechanical Lab and Power House, 1911-1913, 144795 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 5)
      - Correspondence, vouchers and contracts to Whiting Foundry Equipment Company for overhead crane in Power House, 1911-1913, 144794 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 6)
      - Contract with Houston Co-op Manufacturing Company for chemistry tables, 1913, 144793 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 7)
      - Orders to contractor Walworth-English-Flett Company for firemen, 1913, 144792 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 8)
      - Contract with Hoppes Manufacturing Company for feed water heaters, 1913, 144791 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 9)
      - Contract with Wilmer Waldo to construct tunnels and tanks for Mechanical Lab to Admin. building, 1911-1912, 144790 (Box 39, Folder 2, Subfolder 10)
    - Contracts and receipts for construction of various campus buildings, 1910-1913, 144785
      - Contract with Walworth-English-Flett, Co. for various boilers and machinery in Mechanical Lab and Power House, 1911-1913, 144788 (Box 39, Folder 3, Subfolder 1)
      - Contract with Wilmer Waldo for drains and sewers, 1911, 144787 (Box 39, Folder 3, Subfolder 2)
      - Contract with Wilmer Waldo for road gravel, 1910, 144786 (Box 39, Folder 3, Subfolder 3)
    - Vouchers for construction of drains and sewers, 1912, 144784 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Estimates, receipts and vouchers to Wilmer Waldo for payment of construction of various campus buildings, 1911-1913, 144783 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Contract with Wilmer Waldo for construction of roadways, 1911-1913, 144782 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Campus construction contracts, 1911-1916 (1 of 2), 144770
      - W.G. Cornell, plumbing for men's residence hall, 144781 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Albert Pick & Company for chinaware, silverware and glassware, 144780 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
      - Albert Pick & Company for kitchen utensils, 144779 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 3)
      - Blodgett Clock Company, clock for men's residence hall, 144778 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 4)
      - Teas Nursery for tree planting, 144777 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 5)
      - Chicago Gas and Electric Company, for brackets and globes at entrance, 144776 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 6)
      - F.E. Newberry Electric Company for entrance gateway, 144775 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 7)
      - James Stewart and Company for men's residence hall construction, 144774 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 8)
      - William Miller and Sons for stone entrances and gateways, 144773 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 9)
      - F.E. Newberry Electric Company for heating and ventilating in men's residence hall, 144772 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 10)
      - Horton and Horton for construction of South wing, residence hall #2, 144771 (Box 41, Folder 1, Subfolder 11)
    - Campus construction contracts, 1911-1913 (2 of 2), 144762
      - Walworth-English-Flett for kitchen equipment, mens residence hall, 144769 (Box 41, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
      - Bush and Gerts Piano Company for piano rental, 144768 (Box 41, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - Pittsburgh Testing Laboratories for testing steel and cement used in men's residence hall, 144767 (Box 41, Folder 2, Subfolder 3)
      - F.E. Newberry Electric Company for men's residence hall work, 144766 (Box 41, Folder 2, Subfolder 4)
      - Teas Nursery Company for various institute work, 144765 (Box 41, Folder 2, Subfolder 5)
      - James Stewart and Company for construction of dormitory #2, 144764 (Box 41, Folder 2, Subfolder 6)
      - James Stewart and Company for construction of men's residence hall, 144763 (Box 41, Folder 2, Subfolder 7)
    - Contract with Waddell's House Furnishing Company for Administration building and residence hall, 1912-1913, 144761 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Campus construction contracts, 1911-1915, 144753
      - W.H. Nuf, painting, 1912, 144760 (Box 42, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
      - Fred M. Lye, receipt for report on street lighting system, 1913, 144759 (Box 42, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - E.T. Burrows and Company, screens on various buildings, 1912-1913, 144758 (Box 42, Folder 2, Subfolder 3)
      - George T. Hoyt, Company., flags and pennants, 1912-1913, 144757 (Box 42, Folder 2, Subfolder 4)
      - Pittsburgh Testing Company, testing materials on Physics Lab, 1913-1915, 144756 (Box 42, Folder 2, Subfolder 5)
      - Hixon Electric Company, for grounds lights and conduit wiring, 1912-1913, 144755 (Box 42, Folder 2, Subfolder 6)
      - Hixon Electric Company, for electric work on Physics Lab, 1914-1915, 144754 (Box 42, Folder 2, Subfolder 7)
    - Construction for Physical Laboratory by James Stewart and Company, 1913-1914, 144752 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - F.E. Newberry Electric Company, Physics Lab heating, 1914-1915, 144751 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Construction of Physics Lab, 1912-1916, 144739
      - Keithly Company, Inc. for plumbing, 1913-1914, 144750 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 1)
      - Waddell House Furnishings Company, 1914, 144749 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 2)
      - Max Kohl, A.G. Shewitz, Germany - lecture tables, 1914-1916, 144748 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 3)
      - Max Kohl, A.G. Shewitz, Germany - rotary vacuum pump, 1914-1916, 144747 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 4)
      - Shiras Chassing Mfg. Company, lighting fixtures, etc., 1915-1916, 144746 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 5)
      - Houston Hardwood Flooring Company, 1914-1915, 144745 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 6)
      - Randall Lovegrove Company, sump pump, 1914-1915, 144744 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 7)
      - Detroit Heating and Lighting Company. for gas machine, 1914, 144743 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 8)
      - Peerless Rubber Mfg. Company, for rubber mats, 1914, 144742 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 9)
      - Southern Brass Mfg. and Plating Company, 1912, 144741 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 10)
      - Construction of pipe tunnel between Physics Lab and main tunnel, 1914, 144740 (Box 42, Folder 5, Subfolder 11)
    - Construction of Athletic Field House, 1920-1921, 144734
      - Tom Tellepsen, contractor, 1920, 144738 (Box 43, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Barden Electric and Contracting Company, 1920, 144737 (Box 43, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
      - Warren Company, plumbing, 1920-1921, 144736 (Box 43, Folder 1, Subfolder 3)
      - Dixie Heating and Ventilating Company, 1920-1921, 144735 (Box 43, Folder 1, Subfolder 4)
    - Dormitory #2 construction, 1914-1915, 144727
      - Keithly Company, plumbing, 1914, 144733 (Box 43, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
      - Barden Electric Company, 1914-1914, 144732 (Box 43, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - Houston hardwood Flooring Company, receipts, 1915, 144731 (Box 43, Folder 2, Subfolder 3)
      - Peerless Rubber Mfg. Company, rubber mats, 1914-1915, 144730 (Box 43, Folder 2, Subfolder 4)
      - Waddell House Furnishings Company, 1914, 144729 (Box 43, Folder 2, Subfolder 5)
      - F.E. Newberry Electric Company, heating and ventilating, 1914-1915, 144728 (Box 43, Folder 2, Subfolder 6)
    - Various contracts for campus construction, 1914-1925, 144716
      - Hixon Electric Company, experimental electrical work, 1914-1915, 144726 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 1)
      - Warren Company, plumbing in Physical and Biology Labs, 1914-1915, 144725 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 2)
      - Waddell House Furnishings Company, for residence hall, group #2, 1916, 144724 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 3)
      - Barden Electric Company, work on residence hall, group #2, 1916, 144723 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 4)
      - Kinnison Brothers, heating system, residence hall, group #2, 1916-1917, 144722 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 5)
      - Warren Company, plumbing in residence hall, group #2, 1916, 144721 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 6)
      - Houston Construction Company, tunnel work, 1916-1917, 144720 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 7)
      - Houston Construction Company, campus sidewalks, 1917, 144719 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 8)
      - Pittsburgh Testing Laboratories, testing steel and cement, residence hall, group #2, 1917, 144718 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 9)
      - Southern Well Drilling Company, Artesian well on campus, 1921, 144717 (Box 43, Folder 3, Subfolder 10)
    - Construction of Robert and Agnes Cohen House, 1927-1928, 144715 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Temporary water connection and construction of water pipes, 1921, 144714 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Contract with J.B Parker for water connection, 1915, 1921, 144713 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Contract with Southern Steel to construct fire escapes, 1923-1925, 144712 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Fire escape construction, 217 Main St. and others, 1920-1924, 144711 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Chemistry Lab construction, 1923-1927 (1 of 2), 144710 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Chemistry Lab construction, 1923-1927 (2 of 2), 144709 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Contractors for Chemistry Lab construction, 1923-1925, 144700
      - Cram & Ferguson and William Ward Watkin, 1923-1924, 144708 (Box 44, Folder 3, Subfolder 1)
      - Dixie Heating and Ventilating Company, 1923-1925, 144707 (Box 44, Folder 3, Subfolder 2)
      - The Warren Company, plumbing, 1923-1925, 144706 (Box 44, Folder 3, Subfolder 3)
      - A.T. Vick & Company, electrical work, 1923-1925, 144705 (Box 44, Folder 3, Subfolder 4)
      - Kewaunee Mfg. Company, furniture and fixtures, 1924-1925, 144704 (Box 44, Folder 3, Subfolder 5)
      - Furniture and fixtures, no contract, 1924-1925, 144703 (Box 44, Folder 3, Subfolder 6)
      - Jacobe Brothers Electric, electric conduits, 1925, 144702 (Box 44, Folder 3, Subfolder 7)
      - Tellepsen Construction, tunnel connecting Chemistry Lab, 1924, 144701 (Box 44, Folder 3, Subfolder 8)
    - American Construction, steel grandstand, 1926, 144699 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Erection/dismantling of steel bleachers, 1948, 144698 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Contracts for various Rice Institute buildings, 1927-1934, 144690
      - Construction of 2-story building, Milam and Clay, 1927-1928, 144697 (Box 44, Folder 6, Subfolder 1)
      - Construction, Brazos Valley Buick Co., building by Tellepsen Construction, 1928, 144696 (Box 44, Folder 6, Subfolder 2)
      - John Angel, a statue of William M. Rice with monument and tomb, 1929, 144695 (Box 44, Folder 6, Subfolder 3)
      - C.R. Berry & Company, granite pedestal for statue, 1920, 144694 (Box 44, Folder 6, Subfolder 4)
      - William Marsh Rice monument (statue) and tomb construction, Cram & Ferguson, William Ward Watkin, 1929-1930, 144693 (Box 44, Folder 6, Subfolder 5)
      - Repairs to Campanile and Power house, Tellepsen Construction 1930, 144692 (Box 44, Folder 6, Subfolder 6)
      - Contract with G.W. McClure for 1,000 trees for campus, 1930-1934, 144691 (Box 44, Folder 5, Subfolder 7)